blueman.com 2019-07-09

# Read and understand our updated Privacy Policy | Blue Man Group

Last updated on September 19, 2018 

Thank you for visiting the Blue Man Group website at [www.blueman.com](http://www.blueman.com/) (the “Website”) which is owned and operated by Blue Man Group Holdings, LLC (“Blue Man Group,” “we,” “our”, or “us”). Please take the time to read and understand this privacy policy to learn more about our information practices, including the type of information we gather, how such information is collected and used, to whom the information is disclosed, how it is safeguarded and how you can contact us regarding this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”).

By using our Website, you consent to the collection, storage, use and sharing of your information as described in this Privacy Policy, the right to modify this Privacy Policy to adapt it to any technological or legal change, or simply to adjust it to reflect changes made to our Website. Moreover, when you use our Website, you also have responsibilities which are outlined in the [Terms and Conditions](https://www.cirquedusoleil.com/legal/corporate/terms-conditions) section of our Website. We recommend that you consult those Terms and Conditions prior to using our Website in order to inform yourself of your obligations. 

We reserve the right to revise and reissue this Privacy Policy at any time. All updates to our Privacy Policy will be posted on this page. If the changes are material, we may provide you additional notice to your e-mail address. The date of the latest version of this Privacy Policy is indicated at the top of this page. By continuing to use this Website after we post any changes, you are consenting to our use of your information as provided in the modified Privacy Policy. You may also, at any time, communicate with us using the contact information at the bottom of the page in case you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy.

## 1\. Information we collect 

We may collect information about our users in various ways. Namely, we may collect information that you provide to us, we may automatically collect information through your use of the Website, and we may collect information about you from other sources, such as publicly available sources or third parties.

### A. Information you provide to us

You may provide to us personally identifiable information, which is information that could be used to identify you as a specific individual, such as your name, address, phone number or e-mail address (“personal information”) and other information about you, such as demographic information (zip code, gender or similar information) or certain information about your preferences and interests. The Website may collect information about you, including personal information, at various places and forms on the Website, including when you send us an e-mail, enter in contests and sweepstakes, subscribe to newsletters and clubs, submit a job application or post comments, or when you otherwise communicate or interact with us. You are solely responsible for your own personal information in instances where we have not requested that you submit such information to us. Personal information once “de-identified” is not subject to this Privacy Policy and we may treat it as non-personal information and use it without obligation to you except as prohibited by applicable law.

### B. Information collected automatically

We, as well as third-party advertisers, service providers and content providers, may use a variety of technologies (“Tracking Technologies”) that automatically collect certain Website usage information whenever you visit or interact with us (“usage information”). Usage information may include browser type, operating system, all of the areas within our sites and e-mails that you visit, including content that you browse, and the time of day, among other information. Usage information may also include your IP address or other unique identifier (“device identifier”) for the particular device you use to access the Website. A device identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer, mobile phone, or other device used to access the Website and our servers identify your device by its device identifier. Some mobile service providers may also provide us or our third party service providers with information regarding the physical location of the device used to access our Website. 

We may use usage information for a variety of purposes, including to enhance or otherwise improve the Website and our other services. To the extent that we combine usage information with your personal information, we will treat the combined information as personal information under this Privacy Policy. 

The methods that may be used to collect usage information include the following:

#### Cookies

Cookies are small text files that are transferred to your device’s hard drive through your web browser which enable us to retain certain information about your use of the Website, including the date of your last visit to the Website, the pages you visit on the Website, the files you download on the Website and the type of browser you use. We also use cookies and other similar technologies to gather certain information which is generated by your device when you interact with the Website, such as your IP address, computer or mobile device operating system and browser type, the type of mobile device, the address of a referring website (if any), and the pages you visit on the Website. This information is transmitted to us automatically. Cookies may also identify your location. 

Overall, cookies help us to determine the number of people who visit the Website and the frequency of these visits. They also allow us to personalize content, and respond to your requests regarding the Website, our services and shows. In addition, we may use cookies and a variety of other technologies on the Website that collect information for security and fraud detection purposes. You may set your browser to block cookies, including those associated with our services and shows. However, it is important to remember that certain features of the Website may not function properly if your cookies are disabled. You can learn more about cookies by visiting www.allaboutcookies.org which includes additional useful information on cookies and how to block cookies using different types of web browsers. You may also use the "help" function on the toolbar of most web browsers, which will instruct you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have your browser notify you when you receive new cookies and how to disable cookies altogether.

#### Web beacons and pixels

Small graphic images or other web programming code called web beacons (also known as pixels, 1x1 gifs or clear gifs) may be included in the Website pages and e-mail messages from us or our affiliates. Web beacons may be invisible to you, but any electronic image or other web programming code inserted into a web page or e-mail can act as a web beacon. Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes including, without limitation, to count visitors to the sites, to monitor how users navigate the sites, to count how many e-mails sent were actually opened or to count how many forwarded links were actually viewed.

#### Embedded scripts

An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with the sites, such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your device from our web server or a third party service provider, is active only while you are connected to the sites, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.

#### Location-identifying technologies

We may automatically collect the location of your device using your IP address and other data points in order to provide you with our services or tailor our services to your needs. Please note that certain parts of the Website may not function properly without the location data, and that we may be required by law to retain such information. 

Some information about your use of the Website and certain Third Party Services (defined below) may be collected using Tracking Technologies across time and services and used by us and third parties for purposes such as to associate different devices you use, and deliver relevant ads and/or other content to you on the Website and certain Third Party Services. For further information on Tracking Technologies and your choices regarding them, please see the sections entitled “Links to Other Online Services and Third Parties” and “Analytics and Advertising Choices” below.

### C. Information from third parties

We may receive information about you from other sources, including publicly and commercially available sources, as permitted by law, which we may combine with other information we receive from or about you. For example, we may receive information from third parties that sell tickets to Blue Man Group shows, such as Ticketmaster. We are not responsible for the accuracy of any information provided by third parties or third party policies or practices.

## 2\. How we use this information

We may use the information that is submitted through the Website to: 

— Respond to your inquiries, send you service related communications and to provide the services you have requested; 

— Process your transactions; 

— Understand your needs and optimize the Website. For example, we may use your information to help us perform transactions with you more effectively, tailor your experience of the services we offer, secure your transactions by verifying your identity, and suggest appropriate products or services to facilitate your experience of this Website; 

— Send you information that we think might interest you, such as targeted ads and updates about activities, privileges, promotional offers, products and services offered by us and our affiliates; 

— Send you optional surveys to find out more about your opinions of our services and/or our shows; 

— Organize and manage marketing activities, such as contests, games, sweepstakes and other promotions; 

— Improve our Website and services and advertise more effectively by combining your information with other information collected by us from third party sources; 

— Perform quality assurance and business analysis to maintain and improve the quality of the Website and our services; 

— Prevent fraud or potentially illegal activities; 

— Protect the safety of users and Blue Man Group and its affiliates; 

— Comply with our legal obligations;

— Resolve disputes; and 

— Enforce our agreements. 

We may also otherwise use your information with your consent or at your direction.

## 3\. Sharing your information

We may share your information with third parties for any purpose consistent with our statements under this Privacy Policy or as permitted by applicable law, including as follows: 

**Related Companies:** We may share your information with our related companies, including, without limitation, our affiliates, subsidiaries and parent companies, for the purpose of performing services on our behalf or for us, for statistical, advertising, marketing purposes, and internal business purposes. Our related companies may also use your information for their own statistical, advertising and marketing purposes. California Residents have certain rights set forth in the “ Your California Privacy Rights” section below. 

**Service providers:** Your information may be shared with third parties acting on our behalf or for us, such as ticket distributors, data processors, advertisers and technical systems consultants. These service providers are prohibited from using your personal information for any purpose other than to provide this assistance, although we may permit them to use aggregate information which does not identify you or de-identified data for other purposes. 

**Promotional partners:** We may share your information with third parties who may, from time to time, associate themselves with Blue Man Group in connection with activities, such as contests, games, sweepstakes or other promotions. By entering a promotion, you agree to the official rules that govern that promotion, and may, except where prohibited by applicable law, allow the sponsor and/or other parties to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing materials. 

**Social networks:** If you connect with us through a social media account, we may share your information with that social media service. The social media services’ use of the shared information will be governed by the social media services’ privacy policy and your social media account settings. If you do not want your information shared in this way, do not connect your social media service account with our Website or social media accounts. 

**Third parties that provide content advertising or functionality.** When you use our Website, third parties may collect or receive certain information about you and/or your use of the Website (e.g., hashed data, click stream information, browser type, time and date, information about your interactions with advertisements and other content), including through the use of cookies, beacons, and similar Tracking Technologies, in order to provide content, advertising, or functionality or to measure and analyze ad performance, on our Website and social media platforms. This information may be combined with information collected across different websites, online services, and other linked or associated devices.These third parties may use your information to improve their own services and consistent with their own privacy policies. 

**Third parties for their own direct marketing purposes:** We may share your information with other third parties for their own direct marketing purposes (California residents have certain rights set forth in “Your California Privacy Rights ” below). 

**Other parties with your consent:** If you have expressly indicated to us your consent to share information with other third parties that are not included in this list, we may share with such third parties the information you have provided us. Your information may then be used by such third parties in order to provide you with offers, products, promotions and services related to their respective activities or for any other purposes you consent to. 

**Business transaction:** We reserve the right to transfer your information without asking for your express permission in connection with, or during negotiations of, any proposed or actual business transaction such as a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets. However, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to help see to it that your information continues to be used in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. If another company acquires our business or assets, that company will have your information collected by us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your information as allowed by this privacy policy. 

**Legal or administrative process:** We may share your information with third parties if we believe that disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce this Privacy Policy, to detect or prevent fraud, security or technical issues or to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request.

We may also share other information with third parties in a manner that does not identify particular users, including, for example, aggregated data about how users are using our services. Please note that once we share your personal information in accordance with this Section, it shall be processed in accordance with such third parties’ privacy policies.

## 4\. Where your information will be stored

Blue Man Group is headquartered in the United States. If you are accessing the Website from outside of the United States or Canada, please be aware that your information will be collected and stored on servers mainly in the United States and Canada. Data protection laws in the United States and Canada may be different from those of your country of residence. Your use of the Website or provision of any information therefore constitutes your consent to the transfer to and from, processing, usage, sharing and storage of your information, including personal information, in the United States and Canada as set forth in this Privacy Policy. Your information may also be shared with, stored and/or processed by third parties as set out by this Privacy Policy who are located in other countries. For example, some of the service providers acting for us or on our behalf and that process or handle information on our behalf are located outside of the United States and Canada. As a result, your information may be transferred, stored and/or processed outside of the United States and Canada in connection with the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. While we use reasonable means to safeguard your personal information contractually or otherwise with such third parties, your personal information is subject to the legal requirements and governmental authorities of the foreign jurisdictions in which it is located (e.g. we may be legally required to disclose personal information to a governmental authority of a foreign jurisdiction in which your personal information is located).

## 5\. Right to access, correct or delete personal information

Please note that we will retain and use your information only as necessary for the fulfillment of the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy (or for a longer period if required or permitted under applicable laws). You may contact us at any time to consult, correct or remove certain personal information that you have voluntarily submitted to us through the Website. All verifications, comments or requests related to your personal information must be sent in writing using one of the means indicated at the bottom of this page; for purposes of security you will be asked to provide information making it possible to identify you.

You can opt out from receiving e-mails from us or our affiliates at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the e-mails you receive or by communicating with us using the contact information at the bottom of this page. Please note that your opt-out is limited to the e-mail address used and will not affect subsequent subscriptions or non-promotional communications, such as those about your account, transactions, servicing, or our ongoing business relations.

Please note that if you unsubscribe to receiving promotional communications, we may nonetheless continue to use your personal information for data analytics purposes.

## 6\. Links to Other Online Services and third parties

The Website contains content from and hyperlinks to certain third parties' websites, locations, platforms, and serviced (“ **Third Party Services** ”). In addition, our Website contains Tracking Technologies operated by third parties. For example, we use certain third party analytics services, such as Remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting and other integrated services that require Google Analytics to collect data, including the collection of data via cookies and other Tracking Technologies. Similarly, ad serving services, advertisers, and other third parties may use Tracking Technologies on our Website and Third Party Services to track your activities across time and services, and tailor ads to you based on your activities, which may include sending you an ad on a Third Party Service or third party device after you have left the Website (“ **Interest-based Advertising** ”).

You may also choose to give us permission to access information about you from Third Party Services (for example, by linking to social media networks such as Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Instagram, Tumblr and Snapchat).  When you do so, you allow us to collect information based on your settings and in accordance with the privacy policies of such Third Party Services. It is your responsibility to control your settings and to read and understand those privacy policies. Please note, however, that the privacy settings you have set on such Third Party Services do not apply to the information that we have collected. The information we collect through these Third Party Services will be governed by this Privacy Policy. If you publicly reference our Website on a Third Party Service (e.g., by using a hashtag associated with us in a tweet or post), we may use your reference on or in connection with our Website.

Third party Services have privacy practices that may be different from this Privacy Policy. The information collected and stored by third parties, whether through our Website or a Third Party Service, remains subject to their own policies and practices, including what information they share with us, your choices on their services and devices, and whether they store information in the U.S. or elsewhere. We are not responsible for the manner in which your information may be used by said third parties, and encourage you to familiarize yourself with and consult their privacy policies and terms of use. To the extent we combine information we receive from third parties with personal information we collect directly from you on the Website, we will treat the combined information as personal information under this privacy policy.

For further information on Tracking Technologies and your choices regarding them, please see “Information Collected Automatically” above and “Analytics and Advertising Choices” below.

## 7\. Analytics and advertising choices

If you wish to opt-out of your data being used for Google Analytics, you may use one of the [currently available opt-outs](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) for the web. 

You may exercise choices regarding receipt of Interest-based Advertising by submitting opt outs.  Some of the advertisers and service providers that perform advertising-related services for us and our partners may participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance (" **DAA** ") Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. To learn more about how you can exercise certain choices regarding Interest-based Advertising, visit [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).  Some of these companies may also be members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“ **NAI** ”). To learn more about the NAI and your opt out options for their members, see <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>. Please be aware that, even if you are able to opt out of certain kinds of Interest-based Advertising, you may continue to receive other types of ads.  Opting out only means that those selected members should no longer deliver certain Interest-based Advertising to you, but does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content and/or ads (e.g., from other ad networks). We are not responsible for effectiveness of, or compliance with, any third-parties’ opt out options or programs or the accuracy of their statements regarding their programs.

## 8\. Safeguard of your information

We have adopted reasonable security procedures to help protect against loss and misuse of, and unauthorized access to, your information. While we strive to protect your information and privacy, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you share or transmit on the Website, and cannot be responsible for the theft, destruction or inadvertent sharing of your information.

## 9\. Collection of children's personal information

The Website is intended for a general audience and not directed to children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information as defined by the United States Children’s Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) of children under the age of 13 in a manner not permitted by COPPA. If you are a parent or guardian and believe we have collected such information in a manner not permitted by COPPA, please communicate with us using the contact information at the bottom of this page, and we will remove such information to the extent required by COPPA.

## 10\. Your California privacy rights

Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83 (known as the “Shine the Light” law), customers who are residents of California may request certain information about our disclosure of their information during the prior calendar year to third parties and, in some cases, affiliates for those third parties’ and affiliates’ own direct marketing purposes.

Blue Man Group may share personal information as defined by California’s “Shine the Light” law with third parties and/or affiliates for such third parties’ and affiliates’ own direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and wish to obtain information about our compliance with this law, please communicate with us using the contact information at the bottom of this page. Requests must include “California Privacy Rights Request” in the first line of the description and include your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code. Please note that Blue Man Group is not required to respond to requests made by means other than through the provided addresses.

California Business & Professions Code Section 22575(b) (as amended effective January 1, 2014) provides that California residents are entitled to know how Blue Man Group responds to “Do Not Track” browser settings. If activated by you, this setting sends a special signal to the websites you encounter while web browsing indicating that you do not wish to be tracked. Blue Man Group does not respond to Do Not Track signals at this time because a uniform commercial standard has not yet been developed. If we do so in the future, we will update this Privacy Policy to reflect this. For more information on “Do Not Track,” visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

## 11\. Contact us

In case of any questions or comments regarding this Privacy Policy or to keep your personal information accurate and complete, please communicate with us using one of the following contact methods:

E-mail:management@blueman.com

Mail to:

Blue Man Productions,

434 Lafayette St.,

New York, NY 10003

ATTN: Website/legal
